Tapish Khari

contact.tapish@gmail.com

+91-9711075632

linkedin.com/in/tapish-khari-87a12855

https://first-dev-project.vercel.app/#

Summary

I am a Full Stack Developer with 6 years of experience in working with MERN and Java Spring boot Tech Stack where I have played a key role while working on several noteworthy projects.

I am well versed with and proficient in working with technologies like HTML 5, CSS 3, Vanilla JS, JQuery, React JS on the front-end and MongoDB for our NoSQL database and NodeJS, Express on the back-end. I am comfortable in both Monolithic and Microservices Architecture. I am also comfortable in deployment using Github Actions on AWS S3 server or any third party server.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer

VUI Innovate

Jan 2024 - Present

- Built a responsive apparel website named <u>Laurenethan.com</u> using MERN Tech Stack.
- Built an automation tool to Signup, Login in Instagram and follow, like and post a comment on a celebrity Instagram page using Java Selenium.
- Developed an Admin portal of Cipher Sphere Project for a Mobile Application which is similar to WhatsApp .Developed a Message Audit portal which can sniff the backups of last 24hr chats of each users using NodeJs, Express in backend and React library in frontend. The client is Trident Group.

Senior Full Stack Engineer

IPL Global Marine Services

Mar 2021 - Dec 2023

- Lead a team to create a Web application which monitor the arrival and departure of ferry ships based in British Columbia, Canada.
- Created the Responsive and User-friendly UI for a ferry ship cargo deliveryapp to monitor the movement of the ferries across British Columbia.
- Built the Details module of the ferry-ships who are entering the details of the ships.
- Tech Stack is ReactJS and NodeJS and Reporting tool used is Power-Bl and Informatica.

Full Stack Engineer

Camp K12

Jun 2019 - Feb 2021 (1 years 9 months)

- In the Ed Tech company created a web application or a platform where we can connect students and teachers.
- Built a chat application using socket.io and MERN Tech Stack so that teacher and student can chat with each other.
- Built the backend of the login & registration module of an ed-tech application using Node JS with Express JS catering to 1K+ students & teachers on an hourly basis.
- Built an in- house video conferencing module using React JS with WebRTC and integrated it in an ed-tech app to connect students with teachers in real-time.

OUTSCAL Coding Mentor

Outscal

Jun 2020 - Jul 2021 (1 year 2 months)

Mentored students in Data Structures and Algorithms topics.

Director

MadX

Apr 2017 - Jun 2019 (2 years 3 months)

- Managed Operational and Software Development work.
- Created a platform where content writers used to publish their content for their audiences.
- Video of the platform created is given below https://youtu.be/elE7QmUBkyl

Mentorship Track

upGrad

Oct 2015 - Apr 2016 (7 months)

Mentored teams on creating Web Applications to kick start their entrepreneurial journey.

Technology Analyst

ZS Associates

Feb 2014 - Mar 2015 (1 year 2 months)

- At ZS was exposed to Pharma clients like Pfizer, Celgene, GSK.
- Role was of Business Intelligence Analyst. Technologies used was Teradata SQL,PLSQL, Informatica tool and Python programming language.

Publicis Suprement Technical Trainee

Publicis Sapient

Jul 2013 - Feb 2014 (8 months)

- Trained to learn many new technologies ranging from creating Web applications to Mobile app Development.
- Created products which eventually helped Sapient clients to bring revenue for them.

Education

Delhi College of Engineering

Software Engineering, Computer Science

Aug 2009 - May 2013

Graduation Percentage: 71.86%

DAV Dayananad Vihar

High School, PCM

Apr 2007 - Mar 2008

High School Percentage:94%